Guide to the Department of Athletics, Yale University, Records Documenting Polo
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Athletics, Yale University, records documenting polo
1926-2002
RU 908
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.25
The records consist of the files of Daniel J. Wallace, Jr. as coach, scrapbooks, correspondence, and photographs documenting polo at Yale. Also included is a research paper on the sport by Alexandra Redding, Class of 2002.
Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 38-B (YRG 38-B), Records documenting specific sports at Yale.
Existence and Location of Copies
Polo scrapbooks are available on microfilm from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM185. 1984. 1215 frames on 1 reel, 35mm.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred by the Department of Athletics and private donors, 2001-2005.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See inventory for details..
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of the files of Daniel J. Wallace, Jr. as coach, scrapbooks, correspondence, and photographs documenting polo at Yale. Also included is a research paper on the sport by Alexandra Redding, Class of 2002.
College sports; Polo; Photographs; Scrapbooks; Yale University Athletic Association; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University. Dept. of Athletics, Physical Education, and Recreation; Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
- Records of Daniel J. Wallace, Jr., as coach of the Yale polo team, Circa 1937-2000; Accession 2002-A-199
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until January 1, 2035
  - Armory, varsity polo budgets, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photos, trophy (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Horse lists, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Surveys of other college riding programs obtained by Wallace, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Overview of program and budget, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letter to J.C. Rathborne from Yale Polo, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper clippings, originals and photocopies, on Yale Polo. Those from the New Haven Register were carried out under Wallace, who worked there during the time he coached Yale Polo, 1960s- 1970s (Box 1, Folder 7 - 8)
  - Yale Polo Programs, 1960s, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Programs from other college polo programs (Cornell) and from polo clubs where Wallace belonged (Pinehurst) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - United States Polo Association Polo Newsletters, 1960s, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - USPA "25thWomen's National Intercollegiate Polo Tournament." Wallace is featured as the founder of women's intercollegiate polo. Yale Polo history is mentioned, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 12 - 13)
  - Articles on American polo history written by Wallace in "Polo" magazine, 1990s (Box 2, Folder 14 - 17)
  - Alumni list. Correspondence regarding finances, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Budget. Correspondence, 1930s (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Wallace obituary (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - New Haven Register articles on Yale Polo, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Article and correspondence on Yale Polo's record (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Proposed constitution. Yale Polo Association letter, 1930s (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence regarding the Yale Polo Association and other, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 24 - 25)
  - Articles on the history of Yale Polo. Season record sheets 1947-1970 (Box 2, Folder 26 - 27)
  - Yale Polo Association letters. 1942 Yale Polo Association letter concerning the end of polo due to World War Two. 1970s letters and memo regarding the Yale Polo program and its reorganization, 1930s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 28 - 29)
  - Universityof Connecticutarticle on "The Comeback of the Horse." Yale Polo alumni fundraising response, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Letters regarding the Yale Polo capital fund campaign, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Yale Polo season schedules, reports. Letters., 1970s (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Alumni dossier. Fundraising notes., 1970s (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Copies of printed material from binder (Box 3, Folder 34 - 35)
- "The Evolution of Polo in America during the 20th Century,", 2002; Accession 2002-A-200
  The materials are open for research.
  - Redding, Alexandra. "The Evolution of Polo in America during the 20th Century", 2002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Photographs of the polo team, 1928-1930; Accession 2005-A-101
  - Photographs of the polo team, 1928-1930 (Box 1)
- Scrapbooks of the polo team, 1926-1936; Accession 2006-A-036
  Scrapbooks are available on microfilm. Patrons must use HM FILM 185 instead of the original scrapbooks.
  - Scrapbooks
    - 1926-1929 (Box 1, Reel 1U)
    - 1928-1931 (Box 2, Reel 1U)
    - 1931-1936 (Box 3, Reel 1U)
- Records of the polo team, 1981-1988; Accession 2006-A-105
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2023
  - Mills Gifts, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Polo Program Correspondence Endowment, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Lou Lopez, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Memorandum, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - WTY, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Advertising, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Camp, Summer Sports, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Recruitment, 1986-1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Horseshows, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Memorandums/Correspondence, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Memorandums/Correspondence, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Horse Leasing Agreement, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Riding Camp: Marty Smith, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Memorandums, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Rink Operations, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Manure, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 20-21)